

Asghar Ali Mohammed Frontend / UI Developer

My Contact

ali.itechpro@gmail.com

(+61 431 075 716

Sydney, Australia.

asghar.netlify.app

Permanent Resident

Education Background

- Masters in Computer Application
 Sikkim Manipal University, India.
- Bachelors in Commerce (Computers)
 Osmania University, India.
- Post Graduate diploma in Computer Application
 Time Institute, India.
- Diploma in Web designing Opel Multimedia, India.
- Diploma in Dotnet Technologies
 National Institute of Information Tech. India.

About Me

Experienced Frontend / UI developer & UI designer. Skilled at developing user interfaces for web & mobile. Having 6 years experience in Frontend development and 4 years experience in User Interface design. Excellent written and oral communication skills, capable of explaining complex software issues in easy-to-understand terms.

Frontend Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JAVASCRIPT
- REACT
- REDUX
- JQUERY
- REST API

Designing Skills

- PHOTOSHOP
- ADOBE XD
- FIGMA FAMILIRIATY

Others Skills

- GitHub
- Azure CI/CD FAMILIRIATY
- AWS EC2, S3 FAMILIRIATY
- Umbraco
- WordPress
- Visual Studio Code

Achievements

- MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional) Certificate: Transcript ID: 793067, access code: asgharali.
- Received Ibtekar award from the assistant education Minister of Saudi Arabia, the event year 2010.
- Received appreciation/applause for working Non-stop for 26 hours at Mawhiba company, the year 2009.
- Received farewell Award in Mawhiba company, the year 2011.

Professional Experience

Worked as a UI developer in FOXTEL Australia via CloudMarc PVT Ltd.

August 2022 to Dec 2022 - Contract

Key responsibilities:

- Developing User Interface of Newsletters on SFMC (Salesforce marketing cloud).
- Developing Templates, and pages using Html, and CSS.
- Testing and previewing EDMs on Litmus various email clients.
- Making sure it is web-responsive UI for Mobile/Tablet/Desktop
- Solving issues of Cross-Browser compatibility, Cross Platforms (IE, Firefox, Chrome, Safari &, etc.)
- Used various softwares such as Salesforce Marketing Cloud (SFMC), Clickup, and Comm Register for development and tracking work.

Worked as a Frontend Developer for HMASA a non profit organization. *April 2022 to August 2022 - Contract*

Key responsibilities:

- Developing an application on WordPress.
- Applying themes, content, and plugins.
- Administrating the WordPress application.
- Making sure it is web-responsive UI for Mobile/Tablet/Desktop
- Solving issues of Cross-Browser compatibility, Cross Platforms (IE, Firefox, Chrome, Safari &, etc.)
- Deployment Web application on Hosting.

Worked as a UI developer at Ultradata Australia Pty Ltd., Sydney, Australia. Aug 2021 to Nov 2021 - Contract

Key responsibilities:

- Umbraco CMS user interface development.
- Applying to style using SASS to Web applications, mini-sites, and mini apps.
- HTML/CSS/JQuery.
- Developing Web Responsive UI for Mobile/Tablet/Desktop
- Creating HTML/CSS/Javascript/Material Design Lite Template for the web application.
- Solving issues of Cross-Browser compatibility, Cross Platforms (IE, Firefox, Chrome, Safari & etc.)
- Deployment on Azure CI/CD
- JIRA

⋄-----

Worked as a Frontend / UI Developer on multiple projects in Australia. Oct 2018 to June 2021

Projects/Companies:

- APOD(Australian partners of Defence)
- Sydney Computing Solutions PTY LTD.
- Freelancer

т	00	h	0

React, Redux, Html, CSS, Javascript, API, JSON, Bootstrap, Adobe Catalyst CMS.

\$-----

Worked as a Frontend developer and UI/UX designer at King Abdul Aziz Public Library, It's a public library, provide books, magazines and other education information the local residents at Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.

Jun 2013 to Sept 30, 2018 - Full time Permanent

Key responsibilities:

- Developing Web Responsive UI for Mobile/Tablet/Desktop.
- Creating UI for Web and Mobile Apps.
- Solving issues of Cross-Browser compatibility, Cross Platforms (IE, Firefox, Chrome, Safari & etc.)
- UI integration with Dot Net MVC Web Application using Visual Studio.
- Web deployment on hosting services and managing websites/ Web Applications.
- Bootstrap, UI KIT and etc.
- Developing Hybrid Mobile Applications for IOS and Android. jQuery Mobile, Cordova/ Phone Gap.
- Deployment of Mobile apps on IOS App Store, Android Play store.

	Projects	Role and Responsibilities
1	King Abdul Aziz project	In a team, my responsiblity was to design the User Interface and developed frontend then finally integrating UI with ASP.NET MVC Backend Technology.
2	Arabic Union Catalog project	In this project also my responsibility was to design the User Interface and developed frontend then finally integrating UI with ASP.NET Backend Technology. Web responsive, making sure it works well in all the devices
3	Company Reading project	Designed the User Interface in Photoshop and developed frontend then finally integrate UI with ASP.NET Backend Technology.
4	Company Training project	Designing the website, then converting into code html/css/bootstrap and then integrating with backend tech, ASP.NET Backend Technology.
5	King Abdullah website project	My work is offline. User interface, converting into html/css/bootstrap and integration with backend was my involvement as a team.
6	Digital Library project	Designing the website, then converting into code html/css/bootstrap and then integrating with backend tech, ASP.NET Backend Technology.

	Mobile Projects	Role and Responsibilities
1	Public Library android app	Designed the mobile app in photohop, developed app using jquery-mobile/ html/css, phonegap, apache-cordova. Deployed on Google Play
2	Public Library IOS app	Designed the mobile app in photohop, developing app using jquery- mobile/ html/css, phonegap, apache-cordova. Deployed on App store

For more info visit https://asghar.netlify.app/